Wolfgang Köhler Papers 1862-1976 Mss.B.K815
American Philosophical Society
- Series V. Notes, 1930-1966; .5 lin. feet (Box 1-2)
  - Proactive and retroactive inhibition-experimental notes., 1937; 5 items
  - Psychoanalysis finally explained. Copied from "Punch", 1934; 1 item
  - Psychol. Forsch.., 1931-1933; 2 items
  - Psychological Institute., n.d.; 3 items
  - Psychology and Natural Science lecture notes., 2 items
  - Reading notes. Perhaps relating to reply to Lashley., ca. 1951; 2 items
  - Reading to be done., 1953-1965; 8 items
  - Reichenbach, Experience and Prediction notes., 3 items
  - Self regulation notes., n.d.; 1 item
  - Seminar: Classic problems of Philosophy. Swarthmore College, 1948.; 31 items
    Notes of students summaries
  - Seminar at Dartmouth., 1960; 1 item
  - Seminar notes (?)., n.d.; 1 item
  - Seminar notes: Seminar in Systematic Psychology, etc., n.d.; 7 items
  - Seminar outlines, Swarthmore College, 1945-1947; 1 item
  - Subjectivity of objectivity., n.d.; 1 item
  - Swarthmore College Seminar notes (?)., 1944; 19 items
  - Swarthmore College Seminar notes and data., 1939; 6 items
  - Talbot experiments, or reading notes., n.d.; 1 item
  - A Task for Philosophers(?)., n.d.; 1 item
  - Unidentified, n.d.; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, ca. 1951; 5 items
      Found with article by Lashley, Chow and Semmes, "Psychological Review," 1951, vol. 58, 123-136.
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 18 items
  - Wellesley Symposium: "The Scope of Science" notes., n.d.; 1 item
  - What is gestalt psychology? Lecture notes., n.d.; 1 item
  - William James Lecture (? Notes)., n.d.; 1 item
- Series VI. Reports by Assistants, 1949-1965; .5 lin. feet (Box 1)
  Reports prepared by assistants.
  - Adams, P.A. The effects of perceptual grouping., n.d.; 3 items
  - [Adams?, Pauline], n.d.; 2 items
  - Adams, Pauline. Attention and figural after-effects, 7 items
    Date on letters as March
  - Austin, Pauline. Normalization in binocular and monocular vision., 1952-1953; 5 items
  - Austin, Pauline. Set-satiation-polarization., n.d.; 2 items
  - Caroso, John. Trace satiation experiments, and Extrensic Similarity in Formation of Associations., 1958; 3 items
  - Cortical currents in cats., 1951-1952; 11 items
    includes photographs of human subjects with electrodes attached to their head, as well as diagrams of cats' brains.
  - Crawford, H. The law of Pragnanz., 1951; 1 item
  - Dinnerstein?. Data., 1 item
  - Emery. Three dimensional figural after-effects. Simple displacement tables., n.d.; 3 items
  - Figures: The nature of Associations?, n.d.; 16 items
  - Harding, Peggy, and seminar students. Size, Time, Error., 12 items
  - Nachmias, J. Helson's adaptation level theory of psychological judgments., 1951; 1 item
  - The Perception of organization in a list of "isolated" and "crowded" items., 2 items
  - Records: Akustische Untersuchungen., n.d.; 2 items
  - Records of brain currents., 1949; 1 item
  - Satiation experiments (Memory)., 1963; 7 items
  - Satiation experiments materials., n.d.; 17 items
  - Stromeyer material, 1964; 8 items
  - Studies in the perception of sub-organization under conditions of incidental and attentional observing., 1 item
  - Talbot, G. Theodore. Homogeneous electrotonus and the reduction of the Muller-Lyer illusion., 1965; 4 items
  - Talbot data., 1965; 5 items
  - Thorndike data, plus unidentified material., 9 items
  - Unidentified., n.d.; 2 items
  - Unidentified experimental material., n.d.; 25 items
  - Zum Problem des Sukzessivvergleichs bei Tempi., n.d.; 3 items
- Series VII. Research Notebooks, 1914-1959; 1 lin. foot (Box 1-2)
  Consists of 16 research notebooks from different times in Köhelr's career, including his time on Tenerife.
  - No. 1. Research notes: Figural after-effects., n.d.; 1 item
  - No. 2. Notes for lecture on the psycho-physical problem., n.d.; 1 item
    Probably preliminary for lecture on the spycho-physical problem. Seems not to be paper on "Psychologie und Naturwissenschaft." Drafts of letters, including report on grant year.
  - No. 3. Notebook: Tenerife, 1914-1915.; 1 item
  - No. 4. Research notebook, including some experimental data. Swarthmore College., 1941; 10 items
    Included are data on the nature of associations and notes and data on figural after-effects.
  - No. 5. Research notebooks: 1920's., 1 item
    Notes and data.
  - No. 6. Research notebook., 1956-1957; 5 items
    Mainly notes on satiation and figural after-effects.
  - No. 7. Research records and notes, 1929; 1 item
    Some records in handwriting of Lili Köhler.
  - No. 8. Research notebook. Notes, data., 1959; 1 item
  - No. 9. Research notebook., 1931; 1 item
    Data. Some of records in handwriting of Lili Köhler.
  - No. 10. Notebook, 1949; 3 items
  - No. 11. Notebook, 1957; 1 item
  - No. 12. Notebook, 1931; 1 item
  - No. 13. Notebook. Gestalt Psychology., n.d.; 1 item
  - No. 14. Notebook., 1951; 1 item
  - No. 15. Sketch pad., n.d.; 1 item
  - No. 16. Miscellaneous material, used in: "Visual After-effects.", n.d.; 11 items
    See APS Proceedings, Vol 88, no. 4, pp. 269-357
- Series VIII. Photographs and Slides, 1913-1959; 2 lin. feet (Box 1-13)
  Consists of lantern slides of cortical curents, experimental material, graphs, and charts; photographs, slides, and movie reels from Tenerife; and 3 magnetic audio tapes (which includes a birthday greetings from the German Psychological Association).
  - Apes on Tenerife, 1913-1914; 45 images
    - Chimpanzee reaching for bananas, seated chimpanzee looking on., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Chimpanzee, standing on stack of boxes, reaches for hanging bananas, seated chimpanzee in forefront.
    - Chimpanzee reaching for bananas, n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); View of chimpanzee, standing on stack of boxes, reaching for hanging bananas.
  - Intelligenzprufungen an Anthropoiden, ca. 1913; 6 images
  - Visual Perception, Miscellaneous, n.d.; 8 lantern slides
  - Cortical Currents, n.d.; 8 lantern slides
  - London Cortical Currents, 21 lantern slides
  - Currents, n.d.; 24 lantern slides
  - Currents and Illustrations, 28 lantern slides
  - Visual Perception, n.d.; 12 lantern slides, 2 unmounted slides
  - Misc. slides, n.d.; 44 lantern slides,
  - Misc. slides - visual perception, 1938-1964; 15 35mm slides
  - Apes and graphs, 29 glass negatives
  - Misc. negatives, n.d.; 21 negatives
  - Graphs and charts, 60 negatives
  - Charts, n.d.; 31 negatives
  - Graphs, n.d.; 26 negatives
  - Graphs and charts, 27 negatives
  - Slides: Tables, n.d.; 14 lantern slides
  - Unidentified Experimental Material, n.d.; 29 35 mm slides
  - Graphs [originals], n.d.; 2 folders
  - Charts/Graphs, n.d.; 6 folders
  - EXP [Magnetic Tape], n.d.; 1 item
  - CON [Magnetic Tape], n.d.; 1 item
  - Birthday Greetings from German Psychological Association, 1962; 1 item
  - Köhler Ape Films, n.d.; 6 reels
  - Wolfgang Köhler, portrait, n.d; 1 item
  - Claparede, Warren, Koffka, and Köhler in Oxford, 1923; 1 item
  - Köhlers at home in Enfield, NH, 1960s; 1 item
  - Wolfgang Köhler receiving Festschrift, 1962., 1 item; Köhler at presentation of Festschift, standing beside Solomon E. Asch and Edwin B. Newman.
  - Wolfgang Köhler, n.d.; 1 item
  - Wolfgang Köhler at desk, n.d.; 1 item; Portrait of Köhler, seated at desk with papers in background.
  - Wolfgang, Lili, and Karin Köler, 1 item
  - "Summer in Maine" Wolfgang Köhler holding lobster, n.d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Wolfgang Köhler, standing outside, holding lobster.
    General note
    Title taken from typed label on back of photograph.
  - Köhlers' home in Neubabelsberg, a suburb of Berlin, n.d.; 1 item
  - Wolfgang Köhler's office., n.d.; 1 item; View of Köhler's office, with bookcase and desk in background and sofa and table in foreground.
  - Wolfgang Köhler, Ralph Barton Perry, 1934; 1 item
  - Departure for America., ca. 1934; 1.0 Photograph(s) 1 item; Wolfgang Köhler and wife standing near window, inside train, Otto Lauenstein and Karl Duncker standing outside.
  - Lili Köhler, K. S. Lashley on sailboat, n.d.; 1 item
  - Group photograph Rostock, 1929; 1 item
  - Wolfgang Köhler sitting in chair, n.d.; 1 item
  - Lili Köhler, n.d.; 1 item
  - Köhlers' home in Enfield, NH, n.d.; 1 item
  - Wolfgang Köhler, portrait for National Cyclopedia of American Biography, n.d.; 1 item
  - Wolfgang Köhler, portrait, n.d.; 1 item; Formal portrait of Köhler.
  - Wolfgang Köhler, portrait, n.d.; 1 item